

LUONG HUYNH KHANH TRAN

- tran.luonghuynhkhanh@gmail.com
- 💡 Nguyen Trai street, Ward 2, Dist.5, Ho Chi Minh City 📞 0908400656
- in Tran Luong Huynh Khanh 📑 Tran Luong Huynh Khanh

Highly motivated and skilled with 7+ years in retail. Proven in outsourcing, developing products, managing inventory, and boosting sales. Seeking a challenging position to utilize leadership and extensive product assortment, facing, and vendor negotiation skills for a dynamic company's growth.

- WORK EXPERIENCES -

AEON VIETNAM COMPANY LTD.

02/2024 - Now

Merchandising Executive :

In charge of Delicatessen noodle soup including Vietnamese, Japanese, and Korean.

Main Responsibility:

- Outsourcing and negotiating for new suppliers on Price, Trading Terms, Good return, and promotion plans to leverage external expertise and resources.
- Sale and promotion plan to achieve monthly sales target.
- Product development: Oversee the entire product development lifecycle, from ideation to formulation, testing, and production scale-up.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams including the monitor and operation to bring products to the store successfully.
- Conduct market research & competitor surveys to keep updated on market trends and consumer behavior and generate regular reports for senior management.

CENTRAL RETAIL VIETNAM - EBS LTD. COMPANY

03/2022 - 01/2024

Senior Product Developement

Manage all activities related to the procurement of OEM merchandise. Mainly responsible for the Home Accessories team.

Main Responsibility:

- Managing the whole process of product development.
- Building up a yearly product road map and following up on the range according to commercial calendar planning
- Negotiating buying contract terms of the agreement, pricing, and defective products.
- Cooperating with the QC team about product quality for purchase.
- Close work with the logistics and warehouse department to ensure timely delivery.
- Submitting a purchase report, shipment received, stock levels, and place orders needed.
- Attending the International Expo to research potential vendors and update new materials.

SON KIM RETAIL - GS SHOP TVS

10/2019 - 02/2022

Senior Merchandiser Manager

In charge of the Home Living categories.

Brand management: Perfect, Nagakawa, Kangaroo, Kimscook.

Main Responsibility:

- Researching sellers for both TV home shopping and e-commerce platforms.
- Close working with the production team about the script before airing.
- Working with the logistics and QC teams about product inspection and inbound to the warehouse
- For E-Commerce: Creating a monthly campaign for sellers to push a sale up or seasonal stock clearance
- Monthly sales meetings are set up with sellers to review sales performance and the best-selling products.
- Conducting market research to look for new brands, new vendors entering the market, product trends, and consumer behavior.
- Attending International trade fairs to find business cooperation and outsourcing new products.

DONG PHUONG LTD. COMPANY

04/2017 - 09/2019

Merchandise manager

Manage all activities related to the procurement of Akemi, Akemi Uchi, and Studio One merchandise, a well-known Malaysian home textile.

Main Responsibility:

- Evaluating the sales results of the previous season to determine the sales budget proposal for the new season.
- Conduct regular market research to identify and understand the Market's demand.
- Work closely with the team to ensure optimum stock levels and make action plans on product campaigns.
- Cooperating with the logistics and warehouse team to ensure the shipment schedule arrived as planned.
- Coaching sales team on product knowledge and sales skills.
- Working closely with retailers about new store opening projects.

VINGROUP - VINDS

10/2015 - 02/2017

Division Merchandise Manager

In charge of the Sports category

Main Responsibility:

- Managed the merchandise mix and space planning for the new store.
- Being the brand manager equivalent for several franchise brands.
- Collaborate with the Marketing and E-Commerce (Adayroi) MD team to achieve an annual sales plan.
- Stock allocation and replenishment for new and current stores
- Conduct product coaching for store supervisors and staff.
- Working closely with principals to review the monthly sales and marketing reports and submit the OTB for next season.
- Supporting the general manager in developing a buying and selling plan, stock management, a new store opening project, and sourcing new vendors.

PLANET SPORTS VIETNAM

04/2012 - 05/2015

Brand Manager

In charge of the New Balance, Timberland.

Main responsibility:

- Working with the principal country manager to submit the OTB, new store opening, and marketing plan.
- Merchandising and stock control
- Managed shipment and delivery flows.
- We are working closely with retailers about new store opening projections and sale events in department stores.
- Collaborate with the Operation team about monthly promotion schemes to push sales up.
- New product and sales skills coaching for sales supervisors
- Developed B2B and wholesale to maximize sales volume.

VIETNAM INVESTMENT REVIEW- BÁO ĐẦU TƯ

03/2004 - 03/2012

Sale Representative

In charge of four publications: Vietnam Investment Review, Đầu Tư, Đầu Tư Chứng Khoán, Timeout, and special issues.

Main responsibility:

- Selling advertisements and advertorials in the assignment section.
- Seeking sponsors for Friday's review event and special issue publication.
- Closely with the editor department to support the business clients in posting news of their events.
- Giving sales presentations to a range of prospective clients.
- The remaining and developing business partner spends an advertising budget on four publications.

- EDUCATION -

HO CHI MINH CITY OPEN UNIVERSITY

1997 - 2001

Information Technology

- SKILLS -

Communication and Negotiation

Can work under pressure

Team Work

Independent work

Develop Ideas

- CERTIFICATES -

MARKETING MANAGER (2009)

COO - CHIEF CUSTOMER OFFICER (2011)

PUBLIC RELATIONS (2008)

GOOGLE ADS (2022)

OVERSEA TRAINING AT

Malaysia

- ACTIVITIES -

SHARE YOUR LOVE

2011 - Now

Charity Fund

Organize small group to go to poor provinces to give small gifts and health checks.

- LANGUAGES -

EnglishAdvanced

Skills: Listen, Oral, Read and Write communicate by writing a report.

Chinese - Mandarin

Beginer